<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2020-07-15T13:21:32+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Project Minimal</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">42 Days Challenge Complete</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/42complete/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="42 Days Challenge Complete" /><published>2020-07-02T22:42:43+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-02T22:42:43+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/42complete</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/42complete/">&lt;p&gt;About 6 weeks ago, I started the 42 Days Challenge, and now the challenge has ended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still remebered on my 42 Days Challenge blog, I set myself a target: to launch Cashrithm. But sadly that didn’t go as planned.😢&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;here-is-what-i-learned&quot;&gt;Here is what I learned&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-always-have-a-clear-plan&quot;&gt;1. Always have a clear plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often times, in the middle of the challenge I would change my tech stack because eiter I found a better tool or I decided it was too hard to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech Stack I used for this challenge:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firebase&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Node Express&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Git Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-research-research-research&quot;&gt;2. Research Research Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research is extremely important especially when you are still new to this technology. See if you can find similar products from the open-source library or the internet in general and read their code. Not only will this save you time from debugging, but you can also learn from their code architect and see how you can make your program more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-break-tasks-into-smaller-more-manageble-tasks&quot;&gt;3. Break tasks into smaller more manageble tasks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Split the work flow into daily checklists, make them small and accomplishable. Remember your goal is to build up momentum, not finishe everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;END&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really glad this challenge ended, from this challenge I learned a lot of new technology. Backend and frontend, but most importantly I achieved something instead of giving up. I will continue coding this project, and if you are interested check out my next month blog.😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;last-weekly-blog&quot;&gt;Last Weekly Blog&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be my last weekly blog.😢&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain… The main reason why I decided to stop writing weekly blogs are because I need to prep for an upcoming exam. But also I’m getting bored of writing short paragraphs every week. I wouldn’t say my day-to-day life is interesting nor fun, it’s quite plain and repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m switching up the flow. I will be doing monthly blogs instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monthly-blogs&quot;&gt;Monthly Blogs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized monthly blogs are great alternatives. Not only will there be more content for me to write and talk about, but also I get to document the full progress of my challenging and fun projects; as they normally will be completed over a month or two. But also, I’m lazy. 😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further a do, see you next month ~ August… 🍂🍂🍂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my monthly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a monthly blog every month on the first week of Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">About 6 weeks ago, I started the 42 Days Challenge, and now the challenge has ended.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/week6/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 6" /><published>2020-06-26T00:42:43+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-26T00:42:43+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/week6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/week6/">&lt;p&gt;Today is the 26th of June, 4 more days left until Cashrithm is launched.😬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the final week and I haven’t explained the website thoroughly 😂. So this week I have decided to introduce the application I’ve been building for the last 38 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cashrithm&quot;&gt;Cashrithm&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cashrithm, a mix of &lt;strong&gt;Cash&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; aims to support and help small and medium entreprises to track their cashflow using pre-written algorithms. Aiming to provide an accurate data analysis and feedback to the user, reduce their time and effort to track their expenses, or revenue but focus more on their customer or product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it works:&lt;/strong&gt; Cashrithm is a simple website that provides a platform for users to upload their data in csv format, process data with pre-written algorithms and functions then provide an accurate summary of the data such as summing up the Revenue, categorize the Expense and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/home.png&quot; alt=&quot;home&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This is a minimal Dashboard that users will see after Login.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/add.png&quot; alt=&quot;add&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;When you click on the plus button in the Dashboard page, it will direct you to the Add Data page which allow users to upload their csv files.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/sheet.png&quot; alt=&quot;sheet&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;When you click on the created data item it will direct you to a page that displays all the data, categories. Currently this page is still the first version, I will update the UX/UI of this page later.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I create this website? To be honest this idea came from my mom’s friend. It may seem obvious as I have zero experience and knowledge in accountant and finance. But the main reason why I have decided to make this website from scratch is for &lt;strong&gt;fun&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, I actually had the thought of earning a ton of money with this website, but as I started the coding journey the idea of earning money seemed a bit too far and stretched. So instead I took this challenge as a learning journey. I understood more in the backend side of the application such as database, user authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;progress-update-week-6-&quot;&gt;Progress Update: Week 6 📊&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing new was added, but I made the application more scalable as I coded a few functions that could sum up the value, or categorize values when the functions are called.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;function-algorithms-&quot;&gt;Function Algorithms ✅&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sum Algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category Algorithm based on Vender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my weekly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a weekly blog every Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">Today is the 26th of June, 4 more days left until Cashrithm is launched.😬</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/week5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 5" /><published>2020-06-19T00:28:04+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-19T00:28:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/week5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/week5/">&lt;p&gt;It’s now Week 5, time flew by and I only have less than 2 weeks to launch version 1 of &lt;strong&gt;Cashrithm&lt;/strong&gt;. As the deadline gets closer and closer, I can slowly feel the pressure. I’m blaming the pressure on the 42 days challenge I started. Not only do I have to keep the promise I made but also I really wanted to reach my milestone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week was not fun at all, not only do I need to balance my school works but debugging takes forever to get debugged… (Someday when I have the capacity to hire someone, I will definetly hire a debugger. Hear me out.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mvp&quot;&gt;MVP&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I want to introduce a new concept – MVP. MVP stands for &lt;strong&gt;minimum viable product&lt;/strong&gt;, not most valuable player. As a high school programmer and engineerer my connections are pretty limited, let’s be honest I only have less than 10 connections on Linkedin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, that is not the main point. The main point is if you are the general public, &lt;em&gt;cough cough&lt;/em&gt; me included, you and I will not care about the process, but the outcome, the final product and is it useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, as a 16 year old high schooler my resources are pretty limited. No experience, No team members (yes, I am a solo developer for now, if you want to help out please email me), No money. To sum it up, all I have is time and passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can I leverage my resources properly but also meet the market need (produce a product)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-list-out-all-the-must-have-features&quot;&gt;Step 1: List out all the must have features.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming you already have an idea in mind, I will recommend list out all the compulsory features. Make sure they are minimum, removing as many extra features, those aren’t that important for now because they can be added once your MVP is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:
In this project, one of the must-have feature is a database that could store user’s information and sheet information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-find-simple-open-source-tools&quot;&gt;Step 2: Find Simple Open-Source tools.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you want to make a chair there are 3 plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plan A: You make the hammer by yourself by cutting down wood and finding a malleable rock. Then you use the hammer to build the chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plan B: You purchase the hammer, and use it to build the chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plan C: You purchase the chair. (But you don’t have enough money…)💸&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linking that back to coding, Plan B seems to work the best out of the three. So instead of building everything from scratch, the hammer, you use tools that are made prior to your project. In my case Open-Source, there are many open-source materials in the internet decreasing your production time by half but they are also easy to use and free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-test-run&quot;&gt;Step 3: Test Run&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before submitting your project, test run your application. Do a final checkup on every single funciton and detail, make sure everything runs smoothly, before launching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;progress-update-week-5-&quot;&gt;Progress Update: Week 5 📊&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I tackled a few of the boring tasks. Debugging, debugging and debugging. Simple but boring. Will be adding more MVP features in the upcoming weeks, including csv file upload and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;removed-previous-errors-and-bugs-&quot;&gt;Removed previous errors and bugs ✅&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The application can now add multiple sheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Link directly to the database, Firebase Firestore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;View data sheet by sheet id&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;END&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my weekly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a weekly blog every Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">It’s now Week 5, time flew by and I only have less than 2 weeks to launch version 1 of Cashrithm. As the deadline gets closer and closer, I can slowly feel the pressure. I’m blaming the pressure on the 42 days challenge I started. Not only do I have to keep the promise I made but also I really wanted to reach my milestone.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/week4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 4" /><published>2020-06-11T23:28:04+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-11T23:28:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/week4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/week4/">&lt;p&gt;This week’s been productive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this 7 days, I have been working and improving the design basically the user interface or user experience of my website. Although previously I’ve already designed the mockup, but after a bit of research and a bit of experimenting with the color schemes, I’ve decided to redo my design. It was a big commitment as I basically redo the whole entire website, which took me around 4+ hours to finish it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-design&quot;&gt;THE DESIGN&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I bother to redesign and remake the website? Well, first of all layout and design of a product such as a website is extremenly important. Because many people including me &lt;strong&gt;judge a book by its cover&lt;/strong&gt;. Let’s be realistic when people see an aesthetically pleasing website, they will definitely click on it and explore around rather than just close the tab and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I don’t take art, nor a professional designer, but I have common sense. I basically used my instinct to determine whether this page looks good or needed a few changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough talking…Here are a few screen shots of the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/dashboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;layout&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/dataformater.png&quot; alt=&quot;layout&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used neumorphic design to spice up the original mockups. I added a few shadows to the corners making the buttons look more 3D. Clean and minimal are my first priorities. This could help the users maneuver over the website smoothly, removing some friction and hopefully making the website look professional so people won’t notice a high schooler made this. But a ‘designer’ built this. 😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way if you are curious on how I landed this design, I actually did a few googling and testing on Adobe XD before comitting 3+ hours to actually style them on my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Feel free to comment below and give me some suggestions/advice on the design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;progress-update-week-4-&quot;&gt;Progress Update: Week 4 📊&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, it is back on the server side coding. I will be focusing on writing functions. Hopefully it could simplify my existing code and makes the application more scalable for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uxui-design-&quot;&gt;UX/UI Design ✅&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designed a minimal web layout and implemented it to the actual website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;END&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my weekly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a weekly blog every Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">This week’s been productive!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/week3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 3" /><published>2020-06-05T01:48:04+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-05T01:48:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/week3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/week3/">&lt;p&gt;Week 3. Halfway through and 3 more weeks to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to say I have successfully launched a new feature. &lt;strong&gt;Categories algorithm&lt;/strong&gt;, this algorithm is the most difficult algorithm to code out of the other 2. I have been coding this particular section for a few weeks. Many times I was stucked in the infinie loop of bugs, but I am happy to announce the first version of Revenue, Expense, Categories algorithm is successfullly running. 👏👏&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;version-10-features&quot;&gt;Version 1.0 features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/layout.png&quot; alt=&quot;layout&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
Version 1.0 is a bare bone framework and feature of Cashrithm. This will include 3 algorithms that sums up the data, categorize data based on Vender name and filter unecessary data value out based on the google sheet url which the user will input in a given input box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this version is not scalable as the algorithm is only limited to a few data sheet, and the run time is quite slow. In order to make my life simplier and easier in the future, I have decided to convert them into functions. A function for summing up all the value of a given column, a function that categorize value based on the Vender name and many more. In the future, if I wanted to add new algorithms, I can just simply add a few lines of code and Voila the algorithm is running. 👍&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my self-taught coding journey, I’ve learned that &lt;strong&gt;write once run anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; is a super important hack that could save me a ton of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;version-11&quot;&gt;Version 1.1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/summary.png&quot; alt=&quot;summary&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
Since Version 1.0 is the bare bone skeleton of the structure of the program, Version 1.1 should be the fun stuff that gets implemented. I’m still confused by the numbering of the versions, some have 3 digits. I’ll just stick with 2 for now. 😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next 3 weeks, I will be working on version 1.1. Hopefully improving the user experience when they go on my website. But I will also fix some bugs I’ve been avoiding lately (mainly because debugging is a stressful and boring process, let’s hope in the future someone created a machine that could rewrite my code and make it bug-free).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m extremely excited, and hopefully the outcome after 6 weeks could wow myself as this is big milestone for me, personally. 🎯&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;progress-update-week-3-&quot;&gt;Progress Update: Week 3 📊&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I will continue coding the input area where users can control what they want to see in the final summary sheet. On the other hand, I would convert all algorithms into functions that could be called easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;algorithms-&quot;&gt;Algorithms ✅&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;END&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my weekly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a weekly blog every Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">Week 3. Halfway through and 3 more weeks to go!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/week2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 2" /><published>2020-05-29T01:48:04+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-29T01:48:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/week2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/week2/">&lt;p&gt;Week Number Two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is Day 10 of my challenge, to be honest it has been tough since school started and homeworks have been piling up. 😵 I didn’t achieve as much as I intended to, sort of struggling between balancing school and personal projects. But still glad to see my friends again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this week’s progress was bad. On a scale from 1 - 10, I will say it is a solid 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;purpose&quot;&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the very beginning I have always aimed for consistency. But after these 10 Days, things have gotten harder and harder. More bugs, less motivation, more homework (worst thing ever, can’t believe they still exist). Needless to say, this week was stressful and daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with these troublesome problems, I am glad that I still managed to keep my streak of crosses running. Although somedays I only did a short 10 minutes programming session but I kept myself accountable and didn’t give up. 👏👏&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it is way easier to give up then to continue, but I just want to have a complete product. &lt;strong&gt;Just One Single Complete Project&lt;/strong&gt;. Although erros and bugs are unavoidable but having a clear purpose forced me or even kicked me to continue working on this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website might not be used by anyone, but completeing a project means a lot to me. So have a strong clear purpose, a purpose that will someday push or kick you when you feel low and stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plan-for-the-upcoming-week&quot;&gt;Plan for the upcoming week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-category-algorithm&quot;&gt;1. Category algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a bit more complicated than the other 2 algorithms because it consists of two data source instead of one. I have been pushing this feature back for a while so I hope to finish this as soon as possible so it won’t delay my schedule. (not saying that I have a busy schedule.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-input-sheet&quot;&gt;2. Input Sheet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will add more features on the Create New Sheet page. I want to allow users to control the data-output so it is tailor-made. Not only that, but have a friendly user interface. (probably adding that near the end, when every main components are working together) 🤞&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/dataformat.png&quot; alt=&quot;dataformat&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;progress-update-week-2-&quot;&gt;Progress Update: Week 2 📊&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally finished one of the key features which is the algorithm section that fetches data and return a summary of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;algorithms-&quot;&gt;Algorithms ✅&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Revenue algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expense algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;END&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my weekly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a weekly blog every Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">Week Number Two.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/week1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1" /><published>2020-05-22T01:48:04+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-22T01:48:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/week1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/week1/">&lt;p&gt;From last week’s blog, I started and initiated a challenge – 42 days 6 weeks. Within the next 6 weeks, from 20th of May to 30th of June, I will be focusing on one project which is a website that tracks cashflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stage-1-planning-phase&quot;&gt;Stage 1: Planning phase&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the first 2 days to plan out the week. Having a clear vision and purpose in the early stage can highly improve the effiency of the work flow, not only does it give clarity to the work I’m doing but it also motivates me to check off tasks from my list of todos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/design.png&quot; alt=&quot;design&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visualize&quot;&gt;Visualize&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to visualize the outcome and structure of the website. I created this framwork structure that clearly displays the bare bone of my website. From this skeleton framework, it shows how many pages are there on the website, how are they linked and which section needs access to the database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a visual person 👀. Before starting any project, I need to have a broad image of the product in my head. What are the key functions, what does it look like and what special features that makes the application interesting. Creating this design framework above, simply makes me visualize the image of the product clearer. Fun fact, I used different colors to represent different sections: blue = navigation bar, turquoise = algorithms, yellow = sheets etc, so it will look less boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-careful-not-to-get-stuck-in-the-planning-loop&quot;&gt;Be careful not to get stuck in the Planning Loop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people might want to have the perfect plan, however a perfect plan doesn’t exist in my case. Because I’m still a very inexperienced programmer who has been coding for the past 2 years only (sort of, took a few breaks in between).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning is important, but not the most important thing when needed to finish a project. I like to experiment with things. When I did some testing and researches on databases, it broadens my knowledge and view on them. Instead of planning every single step I much prefer experimenting and trying out new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stage-2-start-building&quot;&gt;Stage 2: Start building&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After planning the broad looks and functions of the website, I began to code. First of all, I started adding components. A create new sheet page, login and signup pages for adding new users and a bit of styling to make the page more colorful. (Actually from the design framework above, all the rectangles which are filled in are finished, and the small squares on the top left are database. If I add those squares on specific component, it means they need access to the database.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today will be the end of 3rd day. I still have 4 days to go until the first week is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;here-is-my-plan-so-hear-me-out&quot;&gt;Here is my plan, so hear me out&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;, I will be adding a new component – tabs. This will allow the user to edit and add the name of each tab in the google spreadsheet to the platform. &lt;em&gt;If there’s extra time, I hope to sync the tabs to the database.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;, I will be taking a break. Hopefully able to go on a hike with my mates if the weather is good, preferably sunny and windy day (opitimal hiking weather).☀️💨&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a break is necessary, not only does it frees up your brain from all the clutter you have been stacking up from the week, but it is also good for your mental wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So no work is getting done on Sunday. 😃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday &amp;amp; Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;, debugging time. When adding new features to my website I am pretty sure some unecessary issues and bugs will pop up. I like to leave myself a day or two just to check on the code to see if it runs smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get stressed when things bugs are popping up, especially when the deadline is closing by. So leaving extra time to double check just makes me feel more relaxed on the other hand feeling stressful is an unpleasant feeling and I will do my best to avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;progress-update-week-1-&quot;&gt;Progress Update: Week 1 📊&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really proud of what I did, part of it were already finished before hand such as the user authentication. I wouldn’t totally agree that it is cheating but I have a slight advantage. 😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;planning-phase-&quot;&gt;Planning Phase ✅&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design Framework Completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-authentication-&quot;&gt;User Authentication ✅&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Login user&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signup user&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User created auto syncs to Database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-new-sheet-&quot;&gt;Create New Sheet ✅&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add New Sheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sheet created auto syncs to Database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;END&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my weekly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a weekly blog every Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">From last week’s blog, I started and initiated a challenge – 42 days 6 weeks. Within the next 6 weeks, from 20th of May to 30th of June, I will be focusing on one project which is a website that tracks cashflow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">42 Days | 6 weeks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/42daychallenge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="42 Days | 6 weeks" /><published>2020-05-15T01:48:04+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-15T01:48:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/42daychallenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/42daychallenge/">&lt;p&gt;I have started many projects including a todo app, a weekly blog, an attendance app etc. However many of the projects were abandoned half-way through such as the todo app. Because I find it boring, or I couldn’t move past the bugs. Then I stopped working on that project and pushing it back, like super back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not a great solution as nothing is getting finished and achieved. The cycle keeps repeating. Start a new project, code, debug, give up, and over again. I need a better option to change my cycle so I can actually finish a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I read an article about &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/shapeup/2.2-chapter-08#six-week-cycles&quot;&gt;Six Week Cycles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically in 6 weeks, 42 days, 1008 hours, 60480 minutes, 3628800 seconds you focus on &lt;strong&gt;ONE THING&lt;/strong&gt;. That one thing could be a project you wanted to start, a hobbie you want to expand, an interest you want to understand and dwell into more in depth etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why 6 weeks, well it’s a short period of time that only takes up 1 month and a half. But long enough to finish the whole progress, including build, launch, test, debug etc and actually see the end result. Not only does it give you a period of time to experiment, play around with your project, but it also motivates and pushes you to finish the project you have set to yourself before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if the project succeeded or failed in the end, it only took 6 weeks of your time. Not only it gave you feedback (end result) of the project you are working on, but lets you experiment with creating different projects, exploring different interests and try different hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/42days/42days.png&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting next Wednesday, the 21st of May, I will use this 6 weeks and work on one thing. I am going to plan, start, code, build and launch a website. I chose this specific date to begin with so the last day will be the 30th of June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next 6 weeks, I will update my progress here in this weekly blog. Not only will this keep track on my progress, give an in depth summary on what I’m doing but also share some thoughts and tips whilst doing this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing this 6 weeks, 42 days challenge is very challenging for me, as I still need to go to lessons and do homeworks. But through this challenge, I want to familiarize with my web development skills and get some extra insights on database server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are like me who still needs to go to school or work, I suggest to block a few hours every day to work on your one thing. For me, it would be in the afternoon. If you want to join this challenge with me, feel free to comment on the bottom and tell me what project/hobby/interest are you planning to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-project-im-making-is&quot;&gt;The project I’m making is:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A website platform to keep track of monthly, annual cashflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, I created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/melanie-hsieh-0749a91a9/&quot;&gt;Linkedin Account&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;END&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my weekly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a weekly blog every Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html">I have started many projects including a todo app, a weekly blog, an attendance app etc. However many of the projects were abandoned half-way through such as the todo app. Because I find it boring, or I couldn’t move past the bugs. Then I stopped working on that project and pushing it back, like super back.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My journey on learning to code</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/howilearntocode/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My journey on learning to code" /><published>2020-05-08T01:48:04+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-08T01:48:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/howilearntocode</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/howilearntocode/">&lt;p&gt;Starting from a young age I developed a huge interest in tech. But many might ask how did I learn to code, do I recommend coding bootcamps, why did I start and is coding easy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything must date back after the hackathon ended. If you haven’t read my &lt;a href=&quot;https://melaniehsieh.com/journal/2020/04/17/hackathon.html&quot;&gt;Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; blog feel free to go back and read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summer-coding-class&quot;&gt;Summer coding class&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the hackathon, our group won an award. Guess what, the prize is a coding bootcamp voucher. (It was a $4000 voucher 😱. Next time, I would prefer $4000 in cash. lol. 💵)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So during summer, I used the voucher to join a Basic Javascript class because I wanted to understand more details on creating my own website and how to make it more interactive such as adding animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen promotion videos online talking about coding bootcamps, and how they elevate your coding skills after the bootcamps. I was really optemistic about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, expectation never equals to reality. I swear I have been mentioning this exact line over and over again in many blogs. So in conclusion, I absolutely hated it. Not only was it boring, pointless and time consuming, I didn’t learn anything over the course of 2 weeks. I simply just sat there with my computer on and copying the teacher’s code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I have 0 knowledge in Javascript, after the program my knowledge still remained 0. However from this unsatisfing experience, I found out many free online resources where I can self teach myself to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Melanie Hsieh once said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When there’s free online resources, why would anyone pay extra for the same exact resources. 🤷‍♀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many online resources that are available and free on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-youtube&quot;&gt;1. Youtube&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding has existed since the birth of computers. So many people on youtube will share tips on coding. If you want to learn to code a website, simply type “code a simple website beginner” on the search bar and there will be a list of videos waiting for you to browse. By watching a few of the videos, you can save $4000 and have a finished project working on your computer. 🤯 (I know right, coding is so easy!!! Well technically no. I’ll talk about that later.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-websites&quot;&gt;2. Websites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Freecodecamp&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I self taught myself Javascript with this website, highly recommend it. They include other programming languages such as React, Python, CSS etc. They also have a huge community helping beginners out when you are stuck.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Udacity&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their content are in video format, very clear and easy to understand tutorials/exercises for you to code along. Include topic areas in AI, mobile development, interview prep etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-now&quot;&gt;What now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you learn the basics, you should start creating your own projects just to familiarize with your skills, and practice becuase practice makes perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting a project is easy, but the progress on creating your own project from scratch is hard. As a beginner you will face tons of bugs. Some of them are nonsense, but some you can learn from, such as you missed a semicolon, you have a typo. Coding might &lt;strong&gt;seem&lt;/strong&gt; easy, but in reality it takes time to build up the skills. It took me 2 years to get from beginner to slightly intermediate level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the reason why I continued to code and create softwares is because it makes me feel cool. Some of you may think that sounded stupid and dumb (well you are not alone 😂). I believed that feeling cool is my motivation to continue to create softwares and debug errors. (I laughed when I wrote this line, such nonsense.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I really enjoyed the outcome. From a vision to an actual product that people clicked on it and use, is an unbelievable feeling and satisfaction personally. Although the process is tough and frustrating but once you stepped over the barrier or bug, you will feel extremely proud for 2 seconds and another bug will pop up 😂.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would highly recommend and encourage others to learn to code (and be a nerd like me) but the only criteria is to have a passion in coding/tech. If you don’t find passion in coding, there’s no point on doing it because it’s no fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my friend asked me if I would try singing, I would tell her &lt;strong&gt;NO&lt;/strong&gt; because it’s no fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-fun--boring--waste-of-time--big-brain&quot;&gt;No Fun = Boring = Waste of time (🤯 big brain)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From The Alchemist, Paulo Coelho once wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Remember that wherever your heart is, there you will find your treasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quote sums up everything I just mentioned, so I truely wish everyone luck on finding their own treasure(s). It may be coding, baking, discovering a new island in the middle of atlantic ocean…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck best wishes, and most importantly have &lt;strong&gt;fun&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;END&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my weekly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a weekly blog every Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html">Starting from a young age I developed a huge interest in tech. But many might ask how did I learn to code, do I recommend coding bootcamps, why did I start and is coding easy?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 Summer Internship</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/intern/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 Summer Internship" /><published>2020-05-01T00:48:04+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T00:48:04+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/intern</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/intern/">&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I did a summer internship in a tech startup, MeeOpp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brief-introduction&quot;&gt;Brief Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/meeopp/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MeeOpp is an educational technology start up that provide tailored personalized learning system for students to learn Mandarin. Leveraging technology they are seeking to enhance student’s learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-i-get-in&quot;&gt;How did I get in?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My school hosted a job fair where people from different organizations, companies come to our school to introduce their jobs. I attended a few of them, and one of them was a tech startup co-founder. I was very excited as this was and is my dream job. I wanted to start my own company, change the world and be in fortune 500. During the talk, she mentioned internship oppurtunities for high school students. I really wanted to attend this mainly because I have nothing else to do during summer but also I would like to have a platform to work on my computer coding skills and meet some new people who’s good at tech and coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the fair, I asked for her contact. Long story short, after a few emails and phone calls, I got the internship.😄🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-weeks&quot;&gt;6 weeks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did the internship for 6 full weeks, Monday to Friday and ended the day before school starts. In the beginning, I was extremely nervous as this was my first internship program, but also because I was the youngest member in the whole team.😱&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this 6 week experience, I participated in meetings, redesigned their current profile page and reprogramed their vocabulary flashcard. I learned a lot about frontend development: frameworks, libaries, languages and many more. Throughout this 6 weeks, I realized that coding buddies are really important especially when you faced bugs, they will give you support and feedbacks to help you out. I also got to talk with many developers in the team who has been working in the company for years. They also gave me some advice and a brief introduction on their role in the dev team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;profile-page&quot;&gt;Profile page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First project I worked on was the profile page redesign. Lets be honest I was a complete beginner at the start, knowing little to nothing about UX/UI designs, I did a few design versions on the profile page. They were decent but still lacking a few professional touches. The page size was incorrect, format was wrong, color scheme was messy and all sort of beginner issues.😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;here-is-the-first-version&quot;&gt;Here is the first version:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/meeopp/v1.png&quot; alt=&quot;v1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, throughout the 6 weeks Dawid (not a typo), a UX/UI designer who gave me feedbacks on the format, helped me simplify my profile page, and taught me some tips and tricks in Adobe XD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;here-is-the-final-version-much-neater&quot;&gt;Here is the final version (much neater):&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/meeopp/profile.png&quot; alt=&quot;v1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vocabulary-flashcard&quot;&gt;Vocabulary Flashcard&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second project I worked on was the vocabulary flashcard. I used HTML, CSS and Vanilla Javascript to build the simple easy to use flashcard system. I decided to make it user friendly so I added key press, which is switching slides by simply pressing left arrow, or right arrow key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were day I felt super stressed and unmotivated because I spent a lot of time debugging. But still can’t manage to debug it after many days. Often times going home frustrated, however the other day when I asked William (a more experienced developer than me), he could solve the bug within minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there were also days which I felt extremely proud because the flashcard is finally working. I would say my mood changes a lot throughout the day. I think many developers would agree with me because debugging is a really stressful process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;final-vocabulary-flashcard-yes-i-managed-to-complete-the-redesign&quot;&gt;Final vocabulary flashcard: (Yes, I managed to complete the redesign)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/meeopp/v2.png&quot; alt=&quot;v1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/meeopp/v3.png&quot; alt=&quot;v1&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this internship experience, not only did I met some amazing talented people, but I got some insight on how to run a startup company, how a company is slipt into 2 department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-took-away-a-few-lessons&quot;&gt;I took away a few lessons.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask for help&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When I faced a bug and couldn’t debug it after many tries, asking for help is a quick way to reduce the time of mindless scrolling on stackoverflow. But it also helps you to think in ways that you’ve never thought of, especially when you ask people who are more experienced than you.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;EXPECTATIONS doesn’t equal to REALITY&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Over the past 6 weeks, I feel like coding everyday isn’t my cup of tea as I tend to get impatient about the bugs and I don’t seem to enjoy the process of debugging that much. I realized that my dream career has slightly shifted after this internship oppurtunity as I got the chance to physically experience the process. So I would advice people to experiment with their options instead of just going online and reseach.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Work on something that you are passionate about&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From this internship, I truly experienced why everyone should work in something they are truely passionate and inspired on. As adults, they go to work everyday, working in something they are passionate about just make &lt;strong&gt;work&lt;/strong&gt; feel less sad. As work covers more than 50% of our life time, working in something you like just makes the effort and time spent more worthwhile.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-i-recommend-doing-summer-internship&quot;&gt;Do I recommend doing summer internship?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;yes-definitely&quot;&gt;YES, definitely.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly encourage people to do summer interns because they learn and experiment with things that was never taught in school such as technical skills like React and Adobe XD, but you also gain friendship afterwards. (This is what I called networking 😆)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, 2020, I would like to intern in big companies such as Google, Alibaba, Huawei etc. Big companies and startups often have a lot of differences, mainly because one is big with hundreds of employees, and the latter one just began their journey. But I also wanted to meet like-minded people who is passionate about tech, and also they have cooler products.😆&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;END&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further question you can always email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:melanie@melaniehsieh.com&quot;&gt;melanie@melaniehsieh.com&lt;/a&gt; or find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniehsieh&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscibe to my weekly blog to get the latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading 👀. There will be a weekly blog every Friday, Stay Tuned.😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Melanie Hsieh</name><email>melanie@melaniehsieh.com</email></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html">Last summer, I did a summer internship in a tech startup, MeeOpp.</summary></entry></feed>